# THEO WALCOT

₩ 15.11.1995

@ theowalcot6@hotmail.co.uk

**\** +44 7925971057

in linkedin.com/in/theowalcot

London.UK

# **SUMMARY**

Product manager with experience in both a corporate and start up environment. Expert exposure to data science, artificial intelligence and machine learning leading the vision and requirements for several products in these areas. Also, well equipped with design instincts for a great customer experience in digital products.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Product Management**

#### Filed.ai

Lead Product Manager

December 2020 - Present

- Led a team of 15 developers working on a brand new product as well as a legacy product based on AI/ML. I developed a training and appraisal scheme for my employees as the second most senior person in the business.
- Defined the product requirements and vision through Jira user stories and backlog items, ensuring all stakeholders met their deadlines.
- Built out the knowledge base for the product and developed the go-to-market strategy including building the Google Ads campaigns and setting up the LinkedIn lead generation process.
- Took both products live and led pitches for the company to receive funding from venture capitalists.

#### **Product Management**

#### Sionic

Senior Associate

- # August 2019 December 2020
- Achieved two promotions ahead of standard timeline and received the top performance rating in reviews. Successfully led multiple projects (overseen by partners). This included management of project teams and senior clients up to c-suite level, project planning and tracking. Member of the Sionic Strategy Board.
- Developed a robot for our largest client which would solve generic settlement issues. The robot could email counterparties, match trade date differences and update trade SSIs. Used insights generated from our client to build a product that removed the most timely manual activities and replaced these with automated ones.

## **Technology Management Consulting**

#### **Ernst & Young**

▲ Analyst ☐ July 2017 – August 2019

- Implemented a dashboard application for our client which consolidated and prioritised isolated security logs into key risk areas. This allowed them to better manage their urgent risks.
- Developed the new technology infrastructure which allowed a DevOps functionality to be introduced, reducing the IT change time by 10 percent.
- Led several CSR projects and mentored minority university students.

# **COURSES**

### Product

- Product School, Silicon Valley 2 month Product Management Certificate taught by product leaders at Google, Facebook, Amazon and others. The course laid out the theoretical knowledge needed for working as a PM: Product Strategy, Experimentation Culture, Product/Market Fit and Stakeholder Collaboration
- UI/UX Design Specialisation, California Institute of Arts

#### **Data Science**

- Python Specialisation, University of Michigan
- Applied Data Science with Python Specialisation, University of Michigan
- SQL for Data Science Specialisation, University of California

#### Advanced Technology

- Machine Learning, Stanford University
- Advanced Machine Learning Specialisation, Higher School of Economics
- Deep Learning Specialisation, deeplearning.ai

# **EDUCATION**

#### BSc, Mathematics

## University of Bristol

- 1st class honours, 76 percent, 6th out of 126 in cohort (4.00/4.00 GPA)
- Top of the class academic award for Artificial Intelligence and Financial Mathematics courses

#### A-Levels and GCSEs

Hampton School

m Sept 2007 - June 2014

- A-Levels: A\*A\*AA Maths, Further Maths, Chemistry, Psychology
- GCSEs: 11 A-A\*s
- All-rounder financial scholarship

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Jira
Miro
Adobe XD
Figma
Balsamiq
DataSci (SciPy,NumPy,Pandas)
AI/ML (Scikit and Keras)
Python
R
Matlab
Octave
SQL
UI/UX Design
HTML and CSS

# **EXTRACURRICULAR**

#### Post-university

- Member of Jolt, a business school for self-made people
- Founded Curls London and Masquify, disbanded after producing the MVP due to a saturated market and lack of a Product/Market fit.
- GMAT Score: 780/800

#### **Bristol**

- University of Bristol, 1st XI football team
- Member of the Bristol Data Science Society

## Pre-university

- Brentford Football Academy, Youth EFL and Youth World Cup Finalist
- Hampton School, 1st XI football team

#### Languages

German: advanced reading, intermediate speaking